Tufts Collective for Men Against Violence Records UA218
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Collective for Men Against Violence Records
1991 -- 2008
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Collective for Men Against Violence
Women's Center
UA218
0.7 Linear Feet 2 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series: Subject files.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the records of Tufts Collective for Men Against Violence (formerly Tufts Men Against Violence) and includes correspondence, fliers, manuals, meeting agendas, and material related to their newsletter, The Window. The bulk of the material dates from 1998 to 2002.
Related Materials
UP215, Short Run Publications, DCA.
Biographical / Historical
Tufts Collective for Men Against Violence (TCMAV) was a student-run organization operating from spring 1997 through spring 2002. Up until spring 2001, the organization was called Tufts Men Against Violence. The Mission Statement from TCMAV's Constitution states, "As students concerned with issues surrounding violence, we dedicate ourselves to exploring ourselves and our society, to educating ourselves and others, and to effecting change in the community." Group membership was not limited to men; women were also encouraged to participate. The group published six newsletters, held regular meetings, and participated in several events on campus, including the White Ribbon Campaign, an effort aimed at educating men and boys to end violence against women.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Student life; Student Activities -- Student Government, Clubs, and Organizations; Student activism; Health and Safety
- Subject files, 1991 -- 2008; 1998 -- 2002; UA218.001; 0.75 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains subject files documenting meetings and the newsletter, "The Window." These files date from 1991 through 2002.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in the original order in which it was received.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Membership, 1998 -- 1999; UA218.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Agendas, 1998 -- 1999; UA218.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Contacts, 1995 -- 1998; UA218.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Treasury, 1998 -- 1999; UA218.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - [Geoffrey Canada], 1999; UA218.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - [Meeting notes and Tufts Daily ad], 1998 -- 1999; UA218.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Old members, 1998 -- 1999; UA218.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - TMAV contact lists, 1997 -- 1998; UA218.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Current projects and ads, 1998; UA218.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Peace and justice, 1998 -- 1999; UA218.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Healthy relationships, 1998 -- 1999; UA218.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Sexuality and gender, 1998 -- 1999; UA218.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - [Support services and contacts], 1998 -- 1999; UA218.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Domestic violence, 1991 -- 1998; UA218.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Rape and sexual assault, 1998; UA218.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - TMAV documents, 1997 -- 1998; UA218.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - [Zev Schuman], 1998; UA218.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Notes, 1998; UA218.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - MVP trainer's guide: Mentors in Violence Prevention for college male student-athletes and other student leaders, 1995; UA218.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - [Haymarket People's Fund], 1995 -- 1998; UA218.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - [Articles of gender and sexual violence], 2000 -- 2001; UA218.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Experiencing masculinities: Exercises, activities and resources for teaching and learning about men, 1903 -- 1994; UA218.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Program manual: First stage groups for men who batter, 1998; UA218.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Selected readings on domestic violence, 1998; UA218.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - [The Window and Charles River Publishing, Inc.], 2002; UA218.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Men Against Violence council VI, 2001 -- 2002; UA218.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
    Contains budget information, correspondence, and meeting agendas.
  - [Budget], 1999 -- 2002; UA218.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Men Against Violence 6 - TMAV budget stuff, 2000 -- 2002; UA218.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - [TMAV constitution], 1997 -- 2002; UA218.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Roadmap: The atlas of information on running a student organization, 1997 -- 2002; UA218.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
    This date is approximate.
  - [Budget and TCU treasury procedures manuals], 2000 -- 2003; UA218.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - TCMAV #822 VIII [D0 Luminosity System papers], 2002 -- 2008; UA218.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - TMAV 2000-2001: organization, ideas (other group projects), weekly meeting stuff, member stuff, UA218.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
    This folder included many duplicate copies of TMAV's publication 'The Window' (vol. 3, issues 1 and 2, and vol. 4 issue 2) Issues that were not already present in Short-run student publications UP215 have been moved to UP215, and duplicates have been weeded.
  - [The Window and Charles River Publishing, Inc., 2001; UA218.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - [Drafts of 'The Window' vol. 3, issue 1], 2000; UA218.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Tufts Men Against Violence, 1998 -- 1999; UA218.001.002.00007 (Box 2)